We're going to doing the jump.
What you need to do with the jump is to teach them to go over them on their own, slowly at first.
And by doing that, you just take a treat and tell them, jump.
Good dog!
As they get better and better, you can start raising the jump.
Jump!
Good dog!
A jump can go up to their full height.
With a dog like this, would be up to 24 inches.
We're not going to take her that high.
We're just going to do right over 20 inch.
And Misha jump!
Good girl!
Always treat.
Once they get that down, what you need to do is start adding jumps.
And how you would do that is get them going and do one at a time.
And do, jump!
Good dog!
And jump!
And treat at the end of it.
Always use a lot of praise.
Another thing you can do with the jump is get a stay, sit, sit, good girl!
And you need to start coming over the jumps.
Good girl!
So that they are coming to you and they're not relying you being with them all the time.